Finding Aid for Sidney Fine collected research materials, ca. 1900-1970s
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Sidney Fine collected research materials
circa 1900-1970s
Fine, Sidney, 1920- collector.
88303 Aa 2
Professor of history at the University of Michigan; collected materials pertaining to his research interests.
13 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Professor Sidney Fine (donor no. 3500 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Sidney Fine was a professor of recent American history at the University of Michigan.
This collection consists of that research material accumulated by Sidney Fine in the course of research for his various monographs on the New Deal, the Detroit Riot of 1967, and his study of Walter Drew.
Subjects:
African Americans--Michigan.; Automobile industry and trade--United States.; Detroit (Mich.)--History--20th century.; Automobile industry workers--Labor unions--Michigan.; New Deal, 1933-1939.; General Motors Corporation Sit-Down Strike, 1936-1937.; United States. Automobile Labor Board.; United States. National Recovery Administration.; Riots--Michigan--Detroit--History--20th century.
- Collected research materials
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1933-1936; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Testimony of William Green at the formation of the N.R.A. Automobile Code; also hearing of the Tool and Die Makers Strike in Detroit, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Edgewater, New Jersey ad the Chester, Pennsylvania strikes against the Ford Motor Company; include depositions, 1933-1934 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of the meetings of mediation and negotiation in the Automobile Industry, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Decisions of the Automobile Labor Board, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea; include reports, rules, minutes, documents, etc., 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - N.R.A. code for the automobile industry; also related codes, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous printed reports (Box 1)
  - F.B.I. reports relating to Detroit Riots, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Community Relations Service, Justice Department files re Detroit Riot (largely copies of clippings) (Box 2)
  - Correspondence of Harold Stassen, Gov. of Minnesota, relating to the WPA strike in Minneapolis, 1939; 1 microfilm roll (Box 2)
  - Papers of Emil Hurja, 1932-39, relating to Michigan politics, 1932-1939; 1 microfilm roll (Box 2)
  - Collected materials used in his research on the Detroit Riot of 1967
    (interviews with Nathan Caplan included in box 5)
    - Collected materials used in his research on the Detroit Riot of 1967 (Box 3)
    - Collected materials used in his research on the Detroit Riot of 1967 (Box 4)
      (continued)
    - Collected materials used in his research on the Detroit Riot of 1967 (Box 5)
    - Collected materials used in his research on the Detroit Riot of 1967 (Box 6)
  - Collected material relating to his research on Walter Drew (Box 7)
  - Collected material relating to his research on Walter Drew (Box 8)
  - Collected material relating to his research on Walter Drew (Box 9)
  - Collected material relating to his research on Walter Drew (Box 10)
  - Collected material relating to his research on Walter Drew (Box 11)
  - Collected material relating to his research on Walter Drew (Box 12)
  - Collected material relating to his research on Walter Drew (Box 13)
Related Material
The library also has a collection of Sidney Fine's professional papers, separately cataloged.